Guide to the E. Stanley Shepardson papers, circa 1950s-1980s.
Shepardson, E. Stanley papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
E. Stanley Shepardson papers, circa 1950s-1980s.
21-11-4260
Shepardson, Edwin Stanley,
1
Printed materials, correspondence, newspapers, slides.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection consists primarily of course material.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
E. Stanley Shepardson obtained his B.S. degree from Cornell University in 1936. That same year he joined the extension staff of the Department of Agricultural Engineering at Cornell as an extension instructor in agricultural engineering with responsibilities for 4-H programs in farm electrification. He assisted the WWII Food Production Agency by developing and presenting programs and demonstrations throughout New York State on the repair and maintenance of electric motors and equipment, which were scarce resources due to the war effort. Later, he developed custom spray equipment for potatoes, fruits and vegetables, and trained operators in their use. He subsequently received his M.S. degree from Cornell University in 1947 and that same year was appointed Assistant Professor in the Department of Agricultural Engineering. In 1950, he was promoted to Associate Professor and to Professor in 1958. Stanley also worked abroad with USAID in Israel, IRRI in the Philippines on their agricultural engineering development program, and in Australia with the Commonwealth Scientific and Industry Research Organization's fruit and vegetable harvesting programs. In 1958-59, he was named Acting Head of the department while O. C French was on leave in the Philippines, was Coordinator of Research from 1960-72, and Department Head from 1972 to his retirement in 1978, when he was appointed Professor Emeritus.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection consists primarily of course material.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Shepardson, Edwin Stanley,
Subjects:
Agriculture.; Harvesting.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Resume, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Awards, recognition, obituaries, 1995-1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Memorials, 1996-2000 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Notebook, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- News clippings, 1957-1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- ALC, 1968, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Booklets and articles on drainage, 1958-1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Water heaters, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Bridges etc., 1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Brakes, steering, trucks, 1996-1999 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Water supply, 1968-1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Alumni, 1991-1995 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Cornell fly tyers, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Pumping equipment, 1940, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Grape harvesting research at Cornell, 1960-1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Site plan - sanitary waste disposal renovations, Adirondack League Club, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Sewage plans, Bisby, 1982-1989 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- A.M. Goodman Memorial Library plaque, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Hatchery pipeline, ALC, Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Little Moose sewage system, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Sewage, Bisby, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Sewage plans, ALC, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Sewage, ALC, Date unknown (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Soil and water, 1930's-1970's (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Drainage, Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Machinery and equipment, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Pumping equipment, Undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Repair and remodeling, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Filters, publications and softening, 1962-1967 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- System, 1963, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- #454 Submarine harrow, manufacturers, lectures and correspondence, 1966-1971 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- #454 Submarine harrow, reports, correspondence, sketches, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Slides, 1960's, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)